jelambrar.md 2023-09-29

Jorge Lambraño

Email adress: jelambrar@gmail.com Telephone: (+57) 304-565-3650 Github profile: @jelambrar96 LinkedIn profile: Jorge Lambraño

About me

I am Electronic Engineer from Universidad del Norte (Barranquilla, Colombia). I have experience on the field of Electronic Design and Embedded Systems, and I have skills developing applications using C, Java, C++, JavaScript and Python. He also has experience in the design and development of algorithms

nbia). I s, and nms Data Mining. Additionally, I am leau, QlikView and D3.js. I am a

and knowledge of the principles of Data Science, Machine Learning and Data Mining. Additionally, I am familiar with using data visualization tools such as Grafana, PowerBI, Tableau, QlikView and D3.js. I am a worker oriented towards teamwork and leadership, and with the ability to be independent to achieve objectives. Additionally, I have ability to build and maintain satisfactory interpersonal relationships and to assume responsibilities.

Education

2014-2019: **Electronic Engineer**; Universidad del Norte (Barranquilla-Colombia)

Thesis: Optimización de un sistema de procesamiento de imágenes por radar.

A computer vision system to measure and extract basic ocean waves features were optimized in other to be excuted on devices which medium computing level. New features were developed using python-based frameworks like numpy, scipy and opency-python.

Experience

: Ebenezer Technologies SAS: C++ Developer: (since Feb 2019 to Jun 2021)

- Design and develop of computer vision algorithms to process large amounts of data. C++.
- Create artificial vision models for object detection and tracking. C++.
- Implement Deep Learning and Machine Learning techniques to improve results in artificial vision systems.
- Design and develop Deep Neural Networks to process image data. Python, Tensorflow, Keras.
- Evaluate and debug developed computer vision algorithms to achieve optimal performance. Pytest, PyUnit/UnitTest.
- Use specialized software tools for image processing. Opencv.
- Optimize artificial vision systems for better performance.
- Investigate new trends and artificial vision technologies. More information about Ebenezer Technologies SAS Here.

: Energia Eficiente E2 SA: (since Jul 2021 to Mar 2023)

jelambrar.md 2023-09-29

- Collect and process large volumes of data.
- Use data analysis tools to generate reports. Grafana.
- Design and develop databases to store the collected data. SQL relational and non-relational databases MongoDB, InfluxDB.
- Use data visualization tools to improve data understanding. Grafana, PowerBI, Tableau, QlikView and D3.js.
- Perform predictive analyzes to make informed decisions.
- Develop data mining models to detect patterns and trends.
- Establish information security standards and guarantee data protection. More information about Energia Eficiente SA. Here.

: Pragma SA: (since Mar 2023 to Sep 2023)

- Collect, Analyze and process corporate data.
- Build ETL processes to obtain structuring and unstructured corporate data analysis.
- Implement AWS cloud computing tools for processing structured and unstructured data. AWS Lambda, AWS Glue, AWS S3.
- Implement best security practices and proper management of roles and permissions of stored information.
- Use data visualization tools to improve data understanding. Superset. More information about Pragma SA. Here.

Skills

Programming Languages and Technicals tools

- C/C++
- Docker
- Git
- Java
- Javascript
- Linux
- Python

: Intermediate knowledge of AWS, Angular, Django, Flask, Keras, Pandas, Opencv, NodeJs, TensorFlow, Pandas, Numpy, VHDL

Extra Section

- Human Languages:
 - Spanish (native speaker)
 - English (B2)

Other certifications

• DS4A Colombia 2021: Course. (Sep 2021)

jelambrar.md 2023-09-29

- Habilidades Digitales de Programación de Misión TIC 2022: Course. (Dic 2020)
- NDG Linux Essentials. Course. (Feb 2018)
 Cisco Networking Academy.
- Introduction to IoT. Course (Oct 2017)
 Cisco Networking Academy.
- Uso de clases, objetos, Métodos Y archivos secuenciales en POO con lenguaje de programación
 C++ (Nivel III) Course (Oct 2015)

Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje - SENA

Módulos, estructura de almacenamiento y POO utilizando el lenguaje de programación C++
(Nivel II) Course (Oct 2015)

Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje - SENA

Estructura del lenguaje de programación C++ (Nivel I). Course (May 2015)
 Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje - SENA

Another insteresting projects

: Data science applied to passenger land transport in colombia (Sep 2021)

This project seeks to develop a computational approach based on data science techniques to forecast passenger demand in different bus terminals and routes on Colombia. Passenger transportation companies can find the application useful to make decisions on fleet allocation. Based-python tools were applied: Pandas, Jupyter, Plotly and TensorFlow.

More infomation about this project Here.

: Single Page Application. Animal Care Fundation (Aug 2021)

This application is able to store and display data from an animal care fundation, such as information of each pet, pet care, supplies and costs. Tools like Javascript, MongoDB, NodeJs, ReactJS were applied.

More information about this project Here.